Colin Stevens Baltimore Web Developer

My Portfolio | GitHub Profile | LinkedIn Profile | Colinstevens06@gmail.com | 301-908-2196

Front-end developer with a passion for developing excellent work while providing outstanding customer service. Strong communicator who finds creative solutions to complex problems. Known by my clients for hitting deadlines and looking at the big picture. Known by my friends as loyal and artistic.

Technical Skills

- Advanced knowledge of HTML5, CSS (Bootstrap), Javascript (JQuery), Express, MySQL, APIs, AJAX and Git
- Skilled with Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Moz Keyword Explorer
- Familiar with HandleBars, SASS, Photoshop, Lightroom CC, Illustrator, InDesign and Final Cut Pro

Projects

Group Project: Trivia Game

In this project, I worked with two of my classmates to create a randomized Jeopardy-style trivia game. I wrote code for the gameplay, including the sounds and animations. Questions are generated randomly using a trivia API and AJAX calls. I also helped write CSS to customize our design. The group project also allowed us to work collaboratively in GitHub for the first time, creating new branches and using pull requests to merge our content to the master branch.

- Technologies used: GitHub, AJAX, Local Storage, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, Bulma, HTML
- Links: <u>Deployed Project and GitHub Repository</u>

Weather Dashboard

This project used JQuery and AJAX calls to create a weather dashboard. The user can type in a city name and will get back the weather for the day plus a 5-day forecast. Using local storage, previous queries are saved and available for quick searches. Need to clear your history? There's a button for that, too.

- Technologies used: AJAX, Local Storage, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML
- Links: <u>Deployed Project</u> and <u>GitHub Repository</u>

Team Roster Generator

We recently started the second half of our bootcamp and are transitioning from frontend to backend programming. This roster generator uses NPM's Inquirer project to gather information from a manager. That manager inputs information about their team (built up of engineers and interns). When they're done entering their team's information, a website is generated with the team's information.

- Technologies used: Node.JS, Inquirer, OOP, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstraps, HTML
- GitHub Repository

Education

Johns Hopkins University

Currently Enrolled; Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Towson University

B.A. 12/2010; Majored in Journalism and minored in Business Administration

Professional Experience

Web Project Manager, University of Maryland Medical System, Baltimore, MD, 4/2018-Present

- Oversees major content overhauls to different sections of the website, focusing on service lines which target consumers searching for healthcare services in Baltimore
- Analyzes user traffic, using data to improve our site's user experience
- Researches keywords using various tools, like Moz Pro and Google Search Console, to determine the
 best strategies for search engine optimization. Because of this, we have seen continued increases in
 local traffic to our website
- Partners with physician leaders while developing new consumer-facing web projects

Web Project Coordinator, University of Maryland Medical System, Baltimore, MD, 6/2017-4/2018

- Contributed to the launch of a new system website, playing a key role in content migration and pre-launch content audits
- Managed day-to-day web projects for the University of Maryland Medical Center and System affiliates
- Ensured sites used best practices for Search Engine Optimization, using data to back decisions
- Coordinated implementation of new physician database consisting of more than 4,500 profiles

Communications Specialist, University of Maryland Medical System, Baltimore, MD, 2/2016-6/2017

- Wrote and edited stories for various publications, including quarterly and monthly newsletters
- Managed and executed web projects from conception to completion for two high-priority service lines
- Audited web content, implementing improvements to IA and UX via our CMS
- Maintained physician profiles in the mobile app and online databases

Media Relations Specialist, MD-National Capital Park & Planning Commission, Riverdale, MD, 2/2015-1/2016

- Wrote and distributed news releases
- Pitched stories to media outlets to promote department programs, services and facilities
- Shot, edited, wrote scripts and voiced video packages on departmental programs

Service Manager, Chipotle Mexican Grill, Germantown, MD, 10/2013-6/2014

- Supervised a staff of 30 while managing day-to-day operations
- Oversaw hiring and training of new employees

Sports Reporter, The Gazette, Laurel, MD, 10/2012-7/2013

- Covered the beats for volleyball, ice hockey, boys lacrosse and football
- Developed and pitched multiple stories on a weekly basis
- Used social media frequently to promote stories and break news

Multimedia Sports Reporter, Public Opinion Newspaper, Chambersburg, PA, 8/2011-10/12

- Reported daily on 12 high schools and three colleges on multiple media platforms
- Produced weekly video packages including game coverage, features and talk shows
- Managed multiple social media accounts to promote stories and break news
- Chosen as an award-winning writer for the 2012 Professional Keystone Press Awards, Division IV